<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General | Xinhao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://gaaaavin.github.io/The-Best-Practices/general/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gaaaavin.github.io/The-Best-Practices/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>General</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gaaaavin.github.io/The-Best-Practices/media/icon_hu2a508e6ae6e9a8da6b9815a10a466680_273297_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>https://gaaaavin.github.io/The-Best-Practices/general/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Motivation for This Blog</title>
      <link>https://gaaaavin.github.io/The-Best-Practices/general/motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gaaaavin.github.io/The-Best-Practices/general/motivation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Again, this is NOT a blog about tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-why&#34;&gt;❓ Why&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a researcher who has been involved in various projects and experiments, I have come across numerous instances of incorrect practices being used with common research tools. This incorrect usage has led to flawed results and wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must admit that I too have made some mistakes along the way. However, through my journey, I have learned valuable lessons that have greatly improved my understanding of these tools and their proper usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am eager to share my experiences, insights, and best practices, as if I hoped that there were someone did the same for me when I was a beginner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-the-importance&#34;&gt;⚠️ The Importance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I need to emphasize the importance of best practices in research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, inappropriate practices can affect other users becuase they often lead to abuse of shared resources. In the end, it makes the workflow inefficient for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As researchers, we strive to make meaningful contributions to our domains. Employing the right practices with research tools plays a pivotal role in achieving that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-bridging-the-gap&#34;&gt;🏗️ Bridging the Gap&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a newcomer to the world of research tools, I often found it challenging to locate comprehensive, easy-to-understand resources. Existing documentation can be dense, technical, and difficult to grasp, especially for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My aim in running this blog is to bridge that knowledge gap and provide fellow researchers, particularly newcomers, with practical insights and tips to effectively utilize these tools. I want to make the learning curve less steep for others than it was for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-like-or-contribute&#34;&gt;🌟 Like or contribute&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find this blog useful, please consider giving it a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Gaaaavin/The-Best-Practices&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;star&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or suggestions, please feel free to open an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Gaaaavin/The-Best-Practices/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Gaaaavin/The-Best-Practices/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
